visitdallas.com 2019-06-12

# About the Visit Dallas | Privacy Policy

VISITDALLAS.COM PRIVACY POLICY

Date of Last Revision: 09-24-18

VisitDallas has created this Privacy Policy ("Policy") to disclose how we collect and use Personal Data for our website located at VisitDallas.com (the "Site").

This Policy tells you, among other things, what information we gather from you through our Site, how we may use or disclose that information, and our efforts to protect it.  The Policy addresses the following:

  * "Personal Data" Defined
  * Our Data Protection and Privacy Principles
  * Types of Personal Data We Collect
  * Collection and Use of Personal Data
  * Sharing of Personal Data
  * Non-Identifying Aggregate Information
  * Sharing of Non-Identifying Aggregate Information
  * Retention of Personal Data
  * Cookies
  * Social Plugins and Social Media Widgets
  * Analytics
  * Retention of Personal Data
  * Other Websites
  * Children Under the Age of 13
  * Online Tracking
  * Mergers, Acquisitions, and Other Business Transactions
  * Viewing and Updating Your Personal Data
  * Privacy on Public Forms
  * Choice/Opt Out
  * California Privacy Rights
  * Users in the European Union, European Economic Area, and Switzerland
  * Contact Us
  * Changes to Our Privacy Policy

**"Personal Data" Defined**

As used in this Policy, "Personal Data" means information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.  Personal Data includes your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, and it may include your IP address.

**Our Data Protection and Privacy Principles**

This Site takes every reasonable precaution to protect our users' information.  When you submit payment information via the Site, your information is protected both online and off-line.  For your security, our credit card processing vendor encrypts sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our order forms using secure socket layer technology (SSL). In order for SSL to work, you must have a browser that supports SSL technology. 

It should be noted that information you choose to post to our the Site, e-mails and other information you send to us, except that which you send us on a secure page, is not encrypted and such transmissions cannot be considered a secure means of transmitting information. 

VisitDallas will never ask you to submit your financial data, such as your credit card account numbers, via e-mail.  If you receive an e-mail purporting to be from VisitDallas and requesting that you forward information of this nature by e-mail, please contact us at [privacy@visitdallas.com](mailto:privacy@visitdallas.com). Do not reply directly to the email you received.

You should be aware of the limitations of security, authentication, encryption, and privacy measures used in connection with the Internet and that any information you transmit through the Site may be damaged, corrupted, "sniffed" and/or accessed by another person without your permission. 

Finally, the servers on which we store Personal Data are kept in a secure environment, with access restricted. Regardless of the precautions taken by you or by us, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. We cannot ensure or warrant the ultimate security of any information you transmit. 

**Types of Personal Data We Collect**

Depending upon your use of our Site, we may collect your name, address, zip/postal code number, account log-in and password information, and any information you submit in an online form or survey (such as zip code or age level).  If you make a purchase on our Site, we also will collect your payment information.

Like most websites, we collect usage information about visitors to our Site and how visitors use our Site. This information includes your IP address, date and time of visit, the browser being used, and a list of files downloaded or viewed.

**Collection and Use of Personal Data**

Personal Data is collected primarily to provide a more efficient VisitDallas online experience, help VisitDallas meet your needs, and deliver news and updates you have requested.

  * Information You Provide to Us

If you choose to create a VisitDallas profile or request information from us, we may store some or all of the Personal Data you provide to us to pre-populate forms with your name, address, phone, and email address. We may also use your Personal Data for marketing research and to market to you.

If you provide us with your e-mail address, we will use your e-mail address to communicate information to you regarding our Site and programs affiliated with VisitDallas which may be of interest to you, and to respond to queries.  We also will use your e-mail address to assist you if you forget your log-in information. 

If you have registered for one of our mailing lists or signed up to receive one of our free, electronic newsletters, updates, or e-mail reminders, we will use your email to deliver the requested content.

If you have provided us with Personal Data in connection with a contest, we will use that information to administer the contest and evaluate the use of our Site.

If you have provided us with Personal Data in connection with a survey, we will use that information to monitor the use of our Site and make improvements to the Site.

If you subscribe to a topic, you will be notified by e-mail when a reply is posted to that topic.   

If you choose to save information, such as a meeting planner RFP form, on our Site, we may contact you to follow up on your interest in our convention and meeting services. In such cases, we may employ an outside firm to call you on our behalf. 

We may also use your Personal Data to contact you regarding improvements we can make to our Site and our services. 

  * Usage Data

We use Personal Data collected from your use of our Site to monitor usage and traffic-levels, analyze trends, administer the Site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

**Sharing of Personal Data**

We may share Personal Data with certain third parties in order to further the purpose for which you voluntarily provide VisitDallas with the information or as expressly provided below. For example, VisitDallas engages third party information management service providers to help maintain efficient operations. Because such information management service providers may access our systems, such information management service providers may have access to your information. VisitDallas does not transfer or relinquish ownership of Personal Data maintained about you within its systems and databases to such information management service providers and requires these information management service providers to sign confidentiality agreements to keep all confidential information and other proprietary information found in our systems confidential.  We may also share your Personal Data with our suppliers and vendors as necessary to assist us with fulfilling your requests, payment processing, web services, data analytics, and marketing.  

We may share the information with non-affiliated persons and entities with whom we have a joint marketing agreement to jointly offer products or services, or whose products or services may be offered on our Site.  These companies are contractually forbidden from disclosing or using our customer information other than to carry out the purposes for which the information was disclosed. These companies are in no way authorized to sell, rent, or trade your Personal Data.

We may disclose Personal Data in special cases when we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with the legal process such as, but not limited to situations when we are required to do so by federal, state or local laws and regulations or when we receive a subpoena or are ordered by a court to do so; (b) protect and defend our rights; or (c) act to protect the interests of our users or others. 

We may disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, violation of obligations to us under our Terms of Service or any other agreement or policy, or other illegal activity. 

Except as provided in this Policy, we do not disclose any nonpublic Personal Data about you to anyone except as permitted by law.

**Non-identifying Aggregate Information**

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our Site.

**Sharing of Non-Identifying Aggregate Information**

We may share aggregate information about our users with advertisers, sponsors, and other third parties, though such summary information will not identify you.

We may also provide analysis based on the information we collect to our strategic alliance partners and other risk sharing partners.  The analysis will not identify you.

**Cookies**

We use cookies (a small data file that certain websites write to your hard drive when you visit them), log files, clear gifs or web beacons (known as action tags, pixel tags, spotlight tags or single pixel gifs) information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information such as the services you subscribe to; and (c) to assess the popularity and effectiveness of the material posted on the Site, gain information on how users are making use of the Site, and collect other user information.  We use this information to enhance the user experience during future visits to the Site.  

When you register at the Site, VisitDallas uses a cookie to store a unique, random user ID.  We may use this ID to identify you anonymously in our database and to track information while you are on our Site.  Cookies also enable you to enter the Site as a registered user without having to log on each time.  We might also collect information on the browser type including plug-in versions, for example Flash or QuickTime.  Another example of information we might capture is the URL where a user is entering or exiting the Site.   We may also use web beacons in connection with e-mails sent to users, to let us know whether and when the e-mail was opened.

Some of our marketing partners may set and access cookies and related technologies on your computer.  The cookies may provide information to those partners about your browsing habits and may help them determine if services we provide are being used and to send information that may be of interest to you.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use the Site.  However, if you turn off cookies, then you may not be able to utilize certain features of the Site.

**Social Plugins and Social Media Widgets**

Our Site includes different types of "social plugins" and social media widgets.    

These features may collect your IP address and information on which pages you are visiting on our Site, and they may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

If you do not want to be tracked by social media widgets, log out of all social networks you're logged in to before visiting our websites.

**Analytics**

On this website, we collect demographic data from Google's Interest-based advertising with Google Analytics. Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Settings. Google Analytics' opt-out browser add-on is available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.  

**Retention of Personal Data**

Generally, the Personal Data we obtain about you will be retained up as long as you maintain an account with us or as long as you continue to subscribe to our emails, newsletters, updates, topics, or other communications.  You may ask us to delete your Personal Data at any time, and we will do so unless we are required to maintain that information to comply with applicable laws or we still need the information for the purposes for which it was collected and processed. 

**Other Websites**

The Site may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that VisitDallas is not responsible for the content or the privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site and recommend that they read the privacy statements of each and every website they visit.  This Policy applies solely to information collected by this Site.

**Children Under the Age of 13**

This Site is not directed at children under the age of 13 and VisitDallas does not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of 13.  If VisitDallas obtains actual knowledge that it has obtained Personal Data about a child under the age of 13, that information is immediately and permanently deleted from our records.

**Online Tracking**

VisitDallas does not respond to "do not track" (DNT) signals.

**Mergers, Acquisitions, and Other Business Transactions**

VisitDallas may decide to sell, buy, merge, or otherwise reorganize.  If that occurs, you will be notified via email or a prominent notice on our website of any ownership change and any changes in the use of your Personal Data. These types of transactions may involve the disclosure of Personal Data to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. We seek appropriate protection for Personal Data in these types of transactions.

**Viewing and Updating Your Personal Data**

VisitDallas provides users the following options for changing and modifying Personal Data previously submitted to it.

You can review and revise your Personal Data at any time by accessing your VisitDallas profile on the Site.   

You can update or correct your Personal Data by sending an e-mail to [privacy@visitdallas.com](mailto:privacy@visitdallas.com).

You can update or correct your Personal Data by sending a written request via mail to the following postal address:

VisitDallas  
Attn: Privacy  
325 North St. Paul Street, Suite 700  
Dallas, Texas 75201

To protect your privacy, we will work to verify your identity before granting access to view or revise your Personal Data.

Please note that after VisitDallas processes a change or deletes your Personal Data from active systems and databases, it is possible that non-active residual copies of your information may still exist in systems and on archive or backup media.

**Privacy on Public Forums**

This Site may make chat rooms, forums, and message boards available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your Personal Data.  Such information may be disseminated or used by VisitDallas or its affiliates for any purpose whatsoever, including, but not limited to, marketing related to attracting conventions and visitors to the Dallas area. 

**Choice/Opt Out**

If you prefer that we not disclose your Personal Data to nonaffiliated third parties, you may opt out of those disclosures; that is, you may direct us not to make those disclosures (other than disclosures permitted by law).   If you wish to opt out of disclosures to nonaffiliated third parties, you may e-mail your request to VisitDallas at [privacy@visitdallas.com](mailto:privacy@visitdallas.com).

If you receive communications from us that you do not want to receive, you can opt out from receiving these communications, by specifically telling us to stop sending them to you.  If you wish to opt out of receiving these communications, you can select "Unsubscribe" on any email communication or you can e-mail us at [privacy@visitdallas.com](mailto:privacy@visitdallas.com). We will generally be able to give effect to your withdrawal on 30 days' notice.   

**California Privacy Rights**

If you are a resident of the State of California and VisitDallas has an established business relationship with you, then you have certain privacy rights pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code.  You have the right to request the following at any time:  (a) information from VisitDallas free of charge regarding the manner in which VisitDallas shares certain Personal Data collected through the website with third parties who use that information for direct marketing purposes; and (b) the discontinuation (or opt-out) of VisitDallas's sharing of the information with those third parties.  Please submit any requests ("California Privacy Rights Request") to [privacy@visitdallas.com](mailto:privacy@visitdallas.com) with a subject line of "Your California Privacy Rights."

For each California Privacy Rights Request, please state "Your California Privacy Rights" in the email or letter subject line, and clearly state the following in the body:

  1. the nature of your request;
  2. that the request is related to "Your California Privacy Rights;"
  3. your name, street address, city, state, zip code and email address; and
  4. whether you prefer to receive a response to your request by mail or email.

VisitDallas is not responsible for a California Privacy Rights Request that is incomplete, incorrectly labeled, or incorrectly sent. 

**Users in the European Union, European Economic Area, and Switzerland**

  * Data Controller

VisitDallas is the data controller of the Personal Data you provide on our Site. 

You may contact us by either mail or email.

By mail:

VisitDallas  
Attn: Privacy  
325 North St. Paul Street, Suite 700  
Dallas, Texas 75201

By email: [privacy@visitdallas.com](mailto:privacy@visitdallas.com).

**Purposes of Processing and Legal Basis for Processing**

As explained above, we process Personal Data in various ways depending upon your use of our Site.  We process Personal Data on the following bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform a contract when you request services; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing you with our products and services, enhancing our Site, conducting analytics, and delivering relevant marketing materials.

**Your Rights Regarding Personal Data**

  * Access and Confirmation.  You have the right to ask us if we process Personal Data about you, and in some circumstances, to obtain a copy of your Personal Data. 
  * Deletion and Blocking.  Under certain circumstances, you may have the right to have your Personal Data deleted or blocked without undue delay. 
  * Direct Marketing.  You have the right to object to our processing of Personal Data for direct marketing purposes.
  * Consent.  To the extent we are processing Personal Data on the basis of your consent, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time.
  * Data Portability.  Under certain circumstances, to the extent we are processing your Personal Data on the basis of consent, or that it is necessary to perform a contract with you, and the processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive the Personal Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.

To exercise those rights, please contact us by mail or e-mail at the addressed provided above.

Right to Lodge a Complaint.  You have the right to lodge a complaint about our data collection and processing actions with the supervisory authority in your country.

**Transfers**

We are headquartered in the United States of America. Personal Data may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States. The European Commission has not determined that the United States ensures an adequate level of protection for Personal Data.  

By providing us with Personal Data, you consent to the storage or processing of your Personal Data in the United States and acknowledge that the Personal Data will be subject to the laws of the United States, including the ability of governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies of the United States to obtain disclosure of your Personal Data. 

We will protect the privacy and security of Personal Data according to this Privacy Policy, regardless of where it is processed or stored.

**Contact Us**

Should you have any further questions or suggestions regarding the protection of your Personal Data processed in connection with the use of our websites, please contact us at by mail or email.

By mail:

VisitDallas  
Attn: Privacy  
325 North St. Paul Street, Suite 700  
Dallas, Texas 75201

By email:[privacy@visitdallas.com](mailto:privacy@visitdallas.com)

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We regularly review and revise this Policy. We make changes to the Policy available on this page and note that the Policy has been updated.  If we make material changes to how we treat your Personal Data, we will notify you by either e-mail to the primary e-mail address specified in your account or through a notice on our home page.
